launch.it 2013-11-24

# Privacy | Launch.It

Privacy is our best policy!... not unless it's NEW

Effective Date: 4/10/12

Last Updated Date: 4/10/12

This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into the Launch.it _Terms of Use_.  The term “Launch,” “we,” and “us” includes Launch Ventures Media, Inc. and our affiliates.  The Privacy Policy explains how Launch.it may

  * collect
  * use, and
  * disclose

information it obtains through the Launch.it Service.

The “Launch.it Service” is defined as any website, mobile application, or Internet service under the control of Launch Ventures Media, Inc., whether partial or otherwise, in connection with providing an online platform for Launch’s services.

**Policy Scope.**   This Privacy Policy covers how Launch treats personal information (“Personal Information”) and other information that Launch collects through the Launch.it Service.  

**Personal Information Defined.**   Launch considers “Personal Information” to include information that alone or when in combination with other information may be used to readily identify, contact, or locate you, such as: name, address, email address, or phone number.  Launch does not consider Personal Information to include information that has been anonymized so that it does not allow a third party to easily identify a specific individual.

**Use and Acceptance.**   By using this website or the Launch.it Service and accepting the Terms of Use, you also agree to this Privacy Policy.  If you do not accept this Privacy Policy, you must not use this website or the Launch.it Service.

**New Uses of Personal Information and Other Information.**   From time to time, Launch may use Personal Information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our Privacy Policy.  If our information practices change regarding information previously collected, Launch will make reasonable efforts to provide notice and obtain consent to any such uses as may be required by law.

**Posting of Revised Privacy Policy.**   Launch will post any adjustments to the Privacy Policy on this web page.  The revised version will be effective at the time it is posted.  If you are concerned about how your information is used, bookmark this page and read the Privacy Policy periodically.

**Other Websites and Pages.**   When you navigate away from the Launch.it Service to websites or apps controlled by third parties, you leave the Launch.it Service, at which point this Privacy Policy no longer applies.  You will not receive a notice warning when you leave the Launch.it Service.

**The Launch.it Service Collects Your Information**

**Personal Information Collection.**   You may use parts of the Launch.it Service without creating an account.  However, to post or comment on articles or to interact with other users on the Launch.it Service, such as authors and companies, you must register and create an account.  To register, you will need to provide Personal Information, such as your name, password, and email address.  

You may also register by using your log-in credentials from social networking websites or connect your Launch.it Service account with such websites, including Facebook, Twitter, or LinkedIn.  When you register in this way, we may collect Personal Information from the social networking websites.  For example, when you log in with your Facebook credentials, we collect the Personal Information you have made publicly available in Facebook, such as your name and profile picture.  We may also obtain other information with your permission, such as your gender, date of birth, city, and friend list.  The information the Launch.it Service obtains may depend on your privacy settings with the social networking website.

**Credit Card**[A1]  **Information.**   We may collect billing and credit card information from authors who write sponsored articles.

**Customer Support.**   We may collect Personal Information through your communications with our customer-support team. 

**Cookies, Automatic Data Collection, and Related Technologies.**   In addition, the Launch.it Service collects and stores information that is generated automatically as you use it, including anonymous usage statistics.   

When you visit the Launch.it Service, we and our third-party service providers also receive and record information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, and from cookies and similar technology.  Cookies are small text files that we place in visitors’ computer browsers to store their preferences.  Most browsers allow you to block and delete cookies.  However, if you do that, the Launch.it Service may not work properly.

By using the Launch.it Service, you are authorizing Launch to gather, parse, and retain data related to the provision of the Launch.it Service.

**How Launch Uses Your Information**

**Internal and Service-Related Usage.**   Launch uses Personal Information for internal and service-related purposes only and may provide it to third parties to allow Launch to facilitate the Launch.it Service.  For example, users of the Launch.it Service may view your profile along with the content you publish, or the Launch.it Service may display your Personal Information when you contact other Users using the Launch.it Service.

**Marketing.**   Launch does not rent, sell, or share Personal Information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies for direct marketing purposes **[without your permission]**.  Launch may allow access to other data collected by the Launch.it Service to enable the delivery of online advertising on this website **[or other websites,] [direct marketing and offers,]** or otherwise facilitate transmittal of information that may be useful, relevant, valuable or otherwise of interest to you.

**Improve Service.**   We may retain any data you provide to:

·         Provide customer support;

·         Track the types of questions we receive;

·         Analyze trends;

·         Track user movement;

·         Personalize your experience; and

·         Otherwise enhance the Service.

**Aggregate Data.**   Launch may anonymize and aggregate data, such as demographic information, collected through the Launch.it Service and use it for any purpose.

**Communications.**   We may send email to the email address you provide to us to verify your account and for informational and operational purposes, such as billing, account management, or system maintenance.

**LAUNCH May Disclose Your Information**

**Vendors and Suppliers.**   Launch may share any information it receives with vendors and service providers retained in connection with the provision of the Launch.it Service. 

**Social Networking Websites.   **We may share Personal Information about you, such as your name, if you use the Launch.it Service to share articles with your friends on social networking websites.  The Launch.it Service will share this information only with your friends; however, your friends could share this information with others outside of Launch’s control.

**Search Engines.**   Your content and some Personal Information, such as your name, may be displayed to the public through search engines or similar services when you publish your content on the Launch.it Service.

**As Required By Law and Similar Disclosures**.  We may access, preserve, and disclose your Personal Information, other account information, and content if it believes doing so is required by law or if those actions are reasonably necessary to:

·         comply with legal process, such as a court order or subpoena;

·         enforce this Privacy Policy or Launch.it’s Terms of Use;

·         respond to claims that any content violates the rights of third parties;

·         respond to your requests for customer service;

·         respond to law enforcement;

·         investigate and prevent unauthorized transactions or other illegal activities; or

·         protect our or others’ rights, property, or personal safety.

**Merger, Sale, or Other Asset Transfers.**   Information about you in Launch’s possession may be disclosed as part of a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, sale of company assets, or transition of service to another provider, as well as in the unlikely event of insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which your Personal Information would be transferred as one of the business assets of the company.  Launch does not guarantee that any entity receiving such information in connection with one of these transactions will comply with all terms of this Privacy Policy.

Launch may also disclose your Personal Information with your permission.

**Security of Your Information**

We take steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  Unfortunately, Launch cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit through the Launch.it Service, and you do so at your own risk.  Launch does not accept liability for unintentional disclosure.

By using the Launch.it Service or providing Personal Information to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Launch.it Service.  If we learn of a security system’s breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically by posting a notice on the Launch.it Service or sending an email to you.  You may have a legal right to receive this notice in writing.  To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice), please notify us at [Info@launch.it](mailto:Info@launch.it).

**Children’s Privacy**

Launch does not knowingly collect, maintain, or use any Personal Information from children under 13 years of age.  No part of the Launch.it Service is directed to persons under the age of 13.  In fact, you must be at least 13 years of age to set up an account with the Launch.it Service.  IF YOU ARE UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE, PLEASE DO NOT USE OR ACCESS the Launch.it Service AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER.

If we become aware that we have collected any Personal Information from children under 13, we will promptly delete such information from our databases.  If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained a Launch.it Service account, then you may alert us at [info@launch.it](mailto:info@launch.it) and request that we delete that child’s Personal Information from our systems.

**international users**

By choosing to visit the Launch.it Service or otherwise provide information to Launch, you agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Policy will be governed by the law of the state of New York and the adjudication of any disputes arising in connection with Launch or the Launch.it Service will be in accordance with the [link to _Terms of Use_ ].

**If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use, please note that you are agreeing to the transfer of your Personal Information to the United States to us. By providing your Personal Information you consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Policy.**

**UPDATE YOUR INFORMATION OR POSE A QUESTION OR SUGGESTION**

If you would like to update or correct any information that you have provided to Launch through your use of the Launch.it Service or otherwise, or you have suggestions for improving this Privacy Policy, please send an email to [Info@launch.it](mailto:Info@launch.it).

**Contact Info**

Launch Ventures Media, Inc.

One little west 12th St

New York, New York 10014

Info@launch.it

* * *

 [A1]How is this information being processed and secured?  Do you use third-party vendors?  Are you/they PCI compliant?
